YEE YANG KOK

Software developer at Spencer Ogden

U 0192383575

@ yee_yang94@hotmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/yee-yangkok-116a8893/

Puchong

SUMMARY

https://github.com/kokyeeyang 6 years of full stack web development experience

React portfolio project

https://tour-agency-yy.netlify.app https://bookanymovie.netlify.app

I graduated with a Bachelors in Finance from Drake University in the US. However, seeing the growing potential in the tech industry, I decided to pick up web development at NEXT Academy. I am currently looking to expand and further my knowledge in web development.

Back End Development: PHP, SQL, AJAX, Node JS, TensorflowJS

Front End Development: CSS, HTML, React JS, Javascript, TailwindCSS

PHP Frameworks: Laravel, Codeigniter, Slim, Yii

EXPERIENCE

01/2023 - Present

Kuala Lumpur, Federal Territory of Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

07/2022 - 12/2022

Federal Territory of Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

08/2021 - 06/2022

Federal Territory of Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Software Developer

Spencer Ogden

Oil & Gas recruitment agency

in charge of developing new features and integrations for inhouse KPI systems, as well as database, making predictions for finance department using ML models

- · inhouse data tracking software to keep track of sales consultant results
- · optimizing and writing efficient mysql queries to streamline business processes
- PHP, AJAX, Node JS, Express JS, Javascript

Software Engineer

Poet Farmer

Software House

- · work on City of Rotterdam's website (Drupal) https://www.letoplood.rotterdam.nl/
- · work on International Institute for Democracy and Electoral Assistance website backend (Drupal) https://idea.int/democracytracker
- work on Pedle, an IOT device meant to make life easier for senior citizens. e.g, listening to news, watching Youtube videos and video calling. (Laravel)
- use mysql and PHP to build APIs to be used in the frontend.

Software Engineer (Contractor)

PwC Malaysia

link to PWC marketplace https://marketplace.my.pwc.com

- In charge of expanding and developing features for PWC Marketplace Malaysia, Vietnam and Indonesia
- Expanding Marketplace to other ASEAN regions
- · Fixing backend and frontend issues for Marketplace
- PHP for backend, JS and CSS for frontend, MYSQL for database
- Working in Azure App Service to manage production application backup, create App Services for site and database
- Using Docker container to ensure application integrity and security
- · Streamlining manual work through creative use of Mysql queries

EXPERIENCE

05/2018 - 07/2021

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

SagaOS

Software House

- · Mainly work with PHP, JQuery, CSS, HTML, AWS, SQL
- PHP Frameworks: Codeigniter, Yii, Native, Wordpress, Laravel
- · Proficient at dealing with SQL databases

Junior Software Engineer

- · Adding new features into company's HR system
- · Fixing bugs that occur every now and then
- · Writing APIs
- · Adding new features and reorganizing the layout of the communications portal used by the customer service team
- · Designed a new HR form to be sent out to future interview candidates
- · Designed a back office for the HR department to add new job openings and also deal with interviewees

07/2016 - 07/2017

Des Moines, Iowa Area

Product Management Analyst

Global Atlantic Financial Group

Insurance company

- · Running insurance policy illustrations according to customers' requests and needs
- · Analyzing the effects of interest changes on the maturity dates of insurance products
- · Calculating cash values of policies using actuarial models

05/2015 - 08/2015

Singapore

Marketing Communications Intern

BASF

Chemical company

- · Analyzed competitors to our company's products and their potential threat.
- · Streamlined our clients' efforts to promote our chemical products specifically Hexamoll
- · In charge of writing articles for company's website.
- Responsible for responding to any negative feedback from the public.

EDUCATION

07/2023 - 01/2024

01/2018 - 12/2018

01/2013 - 12/2016

01/2012 - 12/2013

- NodeJs Course **Udemy Alumni**
- Full Stack Web Development

Next Academy

- Bachelor's Degree, Investments and Securities **Drake University**
- Bachelor of Business Administration (B.B.A.) INTI

SKILLS

NodeJs ReactJS TailwindCSS Javascript **PHP MYSQL**